Jacome's Department Store records, 1901-1980
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Jacome's Department Store records, 1901-1980
MS 405
Jacome's Department Store
Records, 1901-1980. This collection includes material regarding company founder Carlos C. Jacome; material regarding company president Alex G. Jacome; company history materials, including photocopies of news clippings; business correspondence; accounting and finance material (mainly business ledgers from 1903 to 1973, including a large payroll ledger covering the years 1939-1950); material related to the Hispanic fraternal benefit society Alianza Hispano-Americana; photographs, including images of Jacome family members, La Bonanza General Store (interior and exterior), and Jacome's Department Store (interior and exterior); real estate documents (legal documents, plans, and blueprints); and scrapbooks.
About 17,000 items 25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
Jacome's Department Store began in 1896 as La Bonanza General Store. Company founder Carlos C. Jacome initially partnered with Loreto Carrillo and opened a store located at 84 West Congress Street, Tucson, Arizona. Jacome then partnered with Genaro S. Manzo in 1902. During their business partnership, Jacome and Manzo were involved with the Alianza Hispano-Americana, a fraternal benefit society for Mexican-Americans. The partnership between Jacome and Manzo was dissolved in 1913 and the store remained within the Jacome family until 1980 (Manzo later returned to work for the store as an employee). In addition to operating La Bonanza, Jacome was involved in Arizona territorial politics. He was the only person of Mexican-descent selected for Arizona's constitutional convention in 1910 and his active membership with the convention contributed to Arizona's obtaining of statehood in 1912. The store's name was changed from La Bonanza to Jacome's Department Store c. 1921 and it was incorporated in 1928. Carlos's son, Alex G. Jacome graduated from the University of Arizona with the degree Bachelor of Science in Business Administration in 1927 and served internships with department stores in New York City and Laredo, Texas before returning to Tucson to work at Jacome's. Alex was named vice-president of the company in 1928. The company's board of directors installed Alex as president upon the death of Carlos in 1932. Alex maintained ties with the University of Arizona throughout his life. He established and oversaw a scholarship fund named in honor of his father. He received the University of Arizona Distinguished Citizen Award in 1966 and he was awarded an honorary Doctor of Laws degree in 1974. Over the years, Alex served on several boards of directors. He also was a member of the Arizona Board of Regents from 1952 to 1961. One of the highlights of Alex's tenure as president of Jacome's was the construction and grand opening of a $1,000,000 store at Stone and Pennington in Tucson in 1951. Alex became chairman of the board of Jacome's in 1972 and his son, Alex F. Jacome, was named president of the company. Alex G. Jacome died in 1980. Jacome's Department Store closed in April of 1980 and its assets were divided among the stockholders.
Store Locations and Expansions
La Bonanza, 84 W. Congress, 1896-1902
La Bonanza, 90 W. Congress, 1902
La Bonanza, 86 W. Congress, 1907
Jacome's Department Store, 87-93 W. Congress, c. 1921-1951 (expanded 1937)
Jacome's Department Store, Stone and Pennington, 1951-1980 (expanded 1957)
Hayden, Arizona, branch store, c. 1943-1954
Arrangement
This collection is organized into ten series.
Series 1: Carlos C. Jacome, Founder; 1904-1933
Series 2: Alex G. Jacome, President; 1941-1979
Series 3: Company History; 1904-1980
Series 4: Business Correspondence; 1905-1978
Series 5: Accounting and Finance; 1903-1980
Series 6: Alianza Hispano-Americana; 1913-1947
Series 7: Photographs; 1922-1966
Series 8: Real Estate; 1901-1980
Series 9: Scrapbooks; 1950-1967
Series 10: Oversized Materials 1939-1979
Scope and Content Note
Records, 1901-1980. Collection consists of the records of Jacome's Department Store, a family-owned business in operation in Tucson, Arizona from 1896 to 1980. The collection contains the papers of company founder Carlos C. Jacome and the papers of his son, long-time company president Alex G. Jacome. A portion of Alex G. Jacome's papers includes personal correspondence with notable politicians including Senators Barry Goldwater and Dennis DeConcini, and Congressmen Morris and Stewart Udall. The collection also includes material relating to company history, including photocopies of news clippings (of note, there is a brief 1950 Time magazine article detailing the building of the new Stone and Pennington store in Tucson); business correspondence; and accounting and finance records. The accounting and finance records, mainly in the form of business ledgers from 1903 to 1973, make up the bulk of the collection. Additionally, the collection includes material related to the Hispanic fraternal benefit society Alianza Hispano-Americana; photographs, including images of Jacome family members, La Bonanza General Store (interior and exterior), and Jacome's Department Store (interior and exterior); real estate documents (legal documents, plans, and blueprints); and scrapbooks (the scrapbooks mainly contain photographs, news clippings, and store advertisements). Several items in the collection are in Spanish-these items consist mostly of correspondence or news clippings.
Jacome's Department Store -- Records and correspondence; La Bonanza General Store -- Records and correspondence; Jacome, Alex G. -- Archives; Jacome, Carlos C. -- Archives; Alianza Hispano-Americana -- Archives; University of Arizona -- Alumni and alumnae; Family-owned business enterprises; Department stores -- Arizona -- Tucson; Stores, Retail -- Tucson, Arizona; Mining claims; Store decoration
Container List
- Series 1: Carlos C. Jacome, Founder; 1904-1933, About 250 items (.4 linear feet)
  This series concerns Carlos C. Jacome, founder of La Bonanza General Store in Tucson, Arizona, which later became Jacome's Department Store. It contains legal documents; correspondence relating to several mining stake claims owned by Carlos; correspondence with family members-particularly with relatives living in Los Angeles and San Francisco, California; correspondence with his attorney, John B. Wright; miscellaneous postcards; and a savings book for an account with the Southern Arizona Bank and Trust Company.
  - Legal; Miscellaneous. 1910-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous; Administrator of Francisco Estrada Estate. 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence; Mining Claims. 1906-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1904-1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1910-1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1923-1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence; Wright, John B., Attorney. 1907-1913 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Postcards; Miscellaneous. 1919-1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Savings Book; Southern Arizona Bank and Trust Company. 1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series 2: Alex G. Jacome, President; 1941-1979, About 1,250 items (1.75 linear feet)
  This series concerns Alex G. Jacome, long-time president of the company and son of Carlos C. Jacome. It contains material regarding board memberships and public service activities; material regarding the bestowal of an honorary degree on Alex by the University of Arizona; speeches; and personal correspondence, including correspondence with Arizona political figures such as Senators Carl Hayden, Paul Fannin, Barry Goldwater, and Dennis DeConcini, and Congressmen Morris and Stewart Udall. Some of the correspondence is in Spanish.
  - Board Memberships; Helio Associates, Inc. 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board Memberships; Helio Associates, Inc. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board Memberships; Helio Associates, Inc. 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board Memberships; Helio Associates, Inc. 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board Memberships; Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company. 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Board Memberships; Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company (1of 4). 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Board Memberships; Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company (2 of 4). 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Board Memberships; Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company (3 of 4). 1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Board Memberships; Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company (4 of 4). 1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Board Memberships; Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company. 1958-1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Board Memberships; Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company (1 of 2). 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Board Memberships; Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company (2 of 2). 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous; European Travel Brochures. 1901-1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous; European Travel Brochures. 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous; Family Tree. 1901-1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous; U.S. Trade Mission to Spain (includes photographs). 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Personal Correspondence; Arizona Research Foundation Board. 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Personal Correspondence; Arizona Statehood Fiftieth Anniversary Stamp. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Personal Correspondence; Arizona-Mexico West Coast Trade Mission. 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Personal Correspondence; Consular Corps of Arizona. 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Personal Correspondence; DeConcini, Senator Dennis. 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Personal Correspondence; Fannin, Senator Paul J. 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Personal Correspondence; Goldwater, Senator Barry M. 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Personal Correspondence; Goldwater, Senator Barry M. 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Personal Correspondence; Goldwater, Senator Barry M. 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Personal Correspondence; Harvill, Richard-Recognition Dinner. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Personal Correspondence; Hayden, Senator Carl. 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Personal Correspondence; Internal Revenue Service (IRS). 1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Personal Correspondence; Carlos C. Jacome Memorial Scholarship. 1944-1979 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Personal Correspondence; "The Jacome Story." 1957 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Personal Correspondence; Jacome's Sunday Closing. 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Personal Correspondence; Mexican Correspondence. 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1901-1980 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1941-1953 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous (1 of 2). 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous (2 of 2). 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1958-1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Personal Correspondence; Miscellaneous. 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Personal Correspondence; Political Correspondence. 1959-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Personal Correspondence; Primer Congreso Industrialde Sonora. 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Personal Correspondence; Rhodes, Senator John J. 1959-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Personal Correspondence; Enrique Rodriguez Hospital Stay. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Personal Correspondence; Selective Service System Board. 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Personal Correspondence; Summer Institute of Linguistics. 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Personal Correspondence; Trade Mission to Spain. 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Personal Correspondence; Udall, Rep. Morris K. 1961-1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Personal Correspondence; Udall, Rep. Stewart L. 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Public Service; Arizona Board of Regents. 1957-1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Public Service; National Citizen's Committee for Public Television. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Public Service; Pima County Hospital Citizens Advisory Committee. 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Public Service; Pima County Hospital Citizens Advisory Committee. 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Public Service; Tucson Airport Authority. 1958-1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Speeches; Miscellaneous. 1963 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - University of Arizona; Honorary Degree. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series 3: Company History; 1904-1980, About 1,500 items (2.25 linear feet)
  The Company History Series contains material about the company's fiftieth anniversary, business associate Genaro S. Manzo, news articles and advertising regarding the Stone and Pennington store that opened in 1951, news clippings relating to the company, Jacome's Department Store circulars, price lists, and wholesalers' catalogs. Several of the news clippings are in Spanish. [Note: Additional Company History items are located in Series 10: Oversized Materials].
  - Anniversary, 50th; Correspondence. 1946 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Anniversary, 50th; Miscellaneous. 1946 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Business Associates; Manzo, Genaro S. 1925-1950 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous; Articles of Incorporation. 1928 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous; Miscellaneous. 1901-1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous; Miscellaneous. 1949-1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - New Store; Department Store Brochures. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - New Store; Proposed Department Area Allocations. 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - New Store; Sketches. 1901-1980 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - News Articles; Miscellaneous. 1938-1980 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Printed Material; Miscellaneous. 1904-1962 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Arizona Advertising Campaign. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Jacome's Circulars. 1901-1980 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Jacome's Circulars. 1951 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Lord & Taylor Cashier's Packing Manual. 1929 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; National Retail Merchants Association Publications. 1901-1980 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; National Retail Merchants Association Publications. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; National Retail Merchants Association Publications. 1976 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; NCR Cash Register Manual. 1901-1980 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Nelly Don, Inc. 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; OPA Base Date Pricing Chart (1 of 2). 1901-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; OPA Base Date Pricing Chart (2 of 2). 1901-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; University of Arizona Retail Sales Class. 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Catalogs (1 of 2). 1901-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Catalogs (2 of 2). 1901-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Catalogs. 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Catalogs. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Catalogs. 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Price Lists. 1901-1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Price Lists. 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Price Lists. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sales, Marketing, and Advertising; Wholesalers' Price Lists. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series 4: Business Correspondence; 1905-1978, About 1,000 items (1.5 linear feet)
  The bulk of the Business Correspondence series is composed of miscellaneous correspondence. The series also contains correspondence with particular wholesalers as well as correspondence on the subject of store events such as Christmas displays and the 1951 new store grand opening for the Stone and Pennington store. Some of the correspondence is in Spanish.
  - Arizona Corporation Commission. 1926 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Arizona State Tax Commission. 1937-1946 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Christmas Club Corporation. 1943-1949 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Christmas Displays. 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Walter T. Dickerson Footwear Company. 1943-1946 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Gruen and Krummeck Architects. 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Houck, Gerald W. 1932-1934 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - The Industrial Commission of Arizona. 1936-1949 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Intermountain Building and Loan Association. 1929-1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Internal Revenue Service. 1929-1946 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Jacome's New Store Grand Opening (1 of 2). 1951 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Jacome's New Store Grand Opening (2 of 2). 1951 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous. 1901-1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous. 1905-1927 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous. 1930-1939 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous. 1940-1946 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous. 1940-1955 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous. 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous. 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company. 1925-1950 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Parking Meters Removal Request. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Small Business Administration Nondiscrimination Compliance. 1978 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Society Brand Clothes. 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Southern Arizona Bank and Trust Company as Trustee for Frank Jacome. 1936 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Series 5: Accounting and Finance; 1903-1980, About 6,000 items (9.0 linear feet)
  The bulk of the Accounting and Finance series consists of bound business ledgers with handwritten entries. Some business ledgers from the Hayden branch store are included in this series. Also, the series contains some statements and reports prepared for the Pima County and state tax commissions. [Note: an oversized payroll ledger for the years 1939-1950 is found in Series 10: Oversized Materials].
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Business Ledgers; Accounts Receivable. 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Business Ledgers; Credit Bureau Report Log. 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Business Ledgers; Daily Charges. 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Business Ledgers; Daily Charges. 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Business Ledgers; Daily Charges. 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Business Ledgers; Daily Charges. 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Business Ledgers; Daily Charges. 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Business Ledgers; Department Sales Figures. 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Business Ledgers; Department Sales Figures. 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Business Ledgers; Department Sales Figures. 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Business Ledgers; Department Sales Figures. 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1903-1918 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Business Ledgers; General (1 of 6). 1928-1938 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Business Ledgers; General (2 of 6). 1928-1938 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Business Ledgers; General (3 of 6). 1928-1938 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Business Ledgers; General (4 of 6). 1928-1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Business Ledgers; General (5 of 6). 1928-1938 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Business Ledgers; General (6 of 6). 1928-1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Business Ledgers; General (1 of 2). 1928-1949 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Business Ledgers; General (2 of 2). 1928-1949 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1939-1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1945-1949 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1949-1953 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1965-1968 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Business Ledgers; General. 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Business Ledgers; Hayden Branch Sales Records. 1943-1951 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Business Ledgers; Hayden Branch Sales Records. 1950-1954 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1952-1955 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1955-1958 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1964-1966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Business Ledgers; Sales Audit Summary and Department Sales Analysis. 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Financial Statements; Miscellaneous. 1907-1947 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Payroll E.D.P. Input Notations. 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Pima County Tax Assessment; Merchant's Personal Property Statement. 1901-1980 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Pima County Tax Assessment; Merchant's Personal Property Statement. 1922-1930 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - State Tax Commission; Sales Tax Audit Report. 1942 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - State Tax Commission; Statement of Income and Expenditures. 1921-1936 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Series 6: Alianza Hispano-Americana; 1913-1947, About 250 items (.4 linear feet)
  This series contains correspondence between Carlos C. Jacome, Genaro S. Manzo, and other members of Alianza Hispano-Americana (AHA). The series also contains a bank book, financial statements, publications, and miscellaneous documents concerning AHA activities. Many items are in Spanish.
  - Arizona v. Alianza Hispano-Americana documents. 1941 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Bank Book. 1926 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence. 1913-1927 (Box 10, Folder 9)